<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?ish ishref="GUID-AD9F445A-D5B5-4EB0-BC05-314C4572018F" version="2" lang="en-US"?><concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="GUID-AD9F445A-D5B5-4EB0-BC05-314C4572018F" xml:lang="en-US" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic concept)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            a(base ishcondition)                            a(base varid)                            a(base varref)                            a(base cid)                            a(base partslist)                            (topic oce-d)                            (topic sdlVariables-c)                            (topic oceCommonElements-c)                            (topic oceMetaDecl-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c concept oceConcept-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c hi-d oceHighlight-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c ui-d oceUi-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c sw-d oceSoftware-c)   " class="- topic/topic concept/concept "><title class="- topic/title ">12 UVgel Wallpaper Factory</title><abstract class="- topic/abstract " id="GUID-85CD5FF6-1002-4A62-B661-C1DE8E5AE706"><p class="- topic/p ">The UVgel Wallpaper Facory is an example of a Colorado 1650 printer with an additional Jumbo Roll Interface that supports the Jumbo Roll media loader at the media input side and a Cutter and Rewinder unit at the media output side.
</p><note class="- topic/note " id="GUID-A56EE1E7-4164-4041-81F8-113F0E4E841B"><p class="- topic/p ">The Colorado 1650 printer and Jumbo Roll interface are Canon branded and the other units are from an external supplier.
</p></note></abstract><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><metadata class="- topic/metadata "><category class="- topic/category ">Functional description</category></metadata></prolog><conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody "><section id="GUID-F5034822-753A-4C8B-A7CD-E44CE7EBD702" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">The UVgel Wallpaper Factory</title><fig id="GUID-12924630-290F-485D-965E-0FB2922C2B47" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-6523AF9B-CD7E-4CFE-A1E5-043580E08992-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-6523AF9B-CD7E-4CFE-A1E5-043580E08992-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The UVgel Wallpaper Factory is a fully modular workflow solution consisting of a motorized Fotoba Jumbo Roll media loader (JRL), which is connected to the front of a Colorado large format roll-to-roll printer. The printer is connected to the Fotoba Cutter XLD 170WP and Rewinder REW 162 to automatically cut flexible media into custom sizes and lengths. And with the embedded taping unit, it's as simple as 'print, cut, rewind and tape'. The job is finished and wallpaper rolls are ready for immediate delivery. For regular print jobs, the two-roll media drawer of the Colorado remains accessible 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The UVgel Wallpaper Factory solution can also be integrated into your existing workflow thanks to the Colorado's open interface structure, giving you the option to choose input and output solutions from different suppliers. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The high-volume media feeder in combination with the productive Colorado printer delivers outstanding production throughput. Automated and unattended, from media input straight to finished output, you can rely on the UVgel Wallpaper Factory to get the job done. Say goodbye to manual operation and achieve full automation to boost your volumes and maximize your profits. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Dimensional stability and color consistency are critical in wallpaper production to ensure a precise match from panel to panel. The benefit of UVgel inks is that they do not require heat to dry, so there is no media distortion with prints produced with the Colorado, resulting in a high quality finished product. And if you're producing large volumes of multi-panel wall coverings, UVgel technology offers maximum control of dot gain and delivers optimal color consistency print after print, even when produced across multiple printers and at different times. Reprint orders with guaranteed color consistency, an essential in the digital wallpaper printing market, are now easier than ever thanks to UVgel technology. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">UVgel inks are odourless and certified GREENGUARD Gold, AgBB, and Type II by ASTM, so wallpapers printed on the Colorado are safe to use indoors. And with the unique FLXfinish technology, you can offer customized wallpaper with a velvety matte finish. 
</p></section></conbody><related-links class="- topic/related-links "><linkpool class="- topic/linkpool " mapkeyref="GUID-8A41CFEA-5928-4042-A2CB-507A5D034160"><link class="- topic/link " mapclass="- map/topicref " format="dita" type="concept" href="generated-topic-GUID-D9491B4E-343C-426B-8F34-F4767B94C217.xml" role="parent"><?ditaot usertext?><linktext class="- topic/linktext "><?ditaot usertext?>Functional description</linktext></link></linkpool></related-links>
</concept>