<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?ish ishref="GUID-F46B97DD-7615-4C90-AA2B-CA124DAC9018" version="4" lang="en-US"?><task xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="GUID-F46B97DD-7615-4C90-AA2B-CA124DAC9018" xml:lang="en-US" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic task)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            a(base ishcondition)                            a(base varid)                            a(base varref)                            a(base cid)                            a(base partslist)                            (topic oce-d)                            (topic sdlVariables-c)                            (topic oceCommonElements-c)                            (topic oceMetaDecl-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c task oceTask-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c hi-d oceHighlight-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c ui-d oceUi-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c sw-d oceSoftware-c)   " class="- topic/topic task/task "><title class="- topic/title ">Usage of functional logging</title><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><metadata class="- topic/metadata "><category class="- topic/category ">Diagnostics</category></metadata></prolog><taskbody class="- topic/body task/taskbody "><section id="GUID-15654A71-0C87-464A-A0E5-25A8D6FE4E04" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Introduction</title><fig id="GUID-9EAE4127-39BE-46E7-B692-C7E0E5DCB86E" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-D4BF512A-02D5-441F-9504-8226912C13E5-low.png" keyref="" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-D4BF512A-02D5-441F-9504-8226912C13E5-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The creation of an image on media in the Colorado starts by loading media in the drawer. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The media is transported towards the platen via the buffer plate. (This plate is used to decouple the forces/movement of the media in the drawer and the platen.) 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The X-transport pinch transports the media over the platen using a controlled media step. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">These steps are measured by the M&amp;C-scanner using the AAC-markers. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">After the media stops moving the printheads are moved over the media to create a small part of the image. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">These steps are repeated until the complete image has been generated. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The settings of the media are stored in the profile. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In the Colorado platform measurements of all kind of sensors are stored in the functional logging. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> A part of this data can be used to diagnose print quality related issues. In the table below the most important logging are summarized. 
</p><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Buffer plate:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This monitors the performance of the buffer plate based on two sensors. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The buffer plate is used to guide the media from the drawer/Jumbo roll to the platen. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> 
<b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Media step:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Using AAC-markers on the media the engine is able to set the correct media steps on the platen. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The data consists of the location of each AAC-marker related to the expected position on the AAC-marker. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Printhead performance:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">After each swath the performance of the printhead is measured using PAINt. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This data can be used to determine the status of each nozzle during printing. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">ECID-information:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Each print job has unique characteristics like media type, profile settings and ink usage. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">All generic information regarding a print job is shown in ECID-information. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Ink expiry date:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The Colorado ink has an expiry date. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">If the ink expires unexpected issues can arise. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This data is based on the calculation of the expiry date in the ink tanks. 
</p></li></ol></section><section id="GUID-FFE645C5-1E98-4783-B7FB-17FE48CEC034" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Buffer plate</title><p class="- topic/p ">The buffer plate performs 2 important functions related to print quality. (See also : 
<xref keyref="15FUNC02" class="- topic/xref " href="GUID-32697AF0-BC89-480B-812D-46AF0F253E61.xml" format="dita" locktitle="yes" type="concept"><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text 15 The function of the buffer?>15 The function of the buffer</xref>). 
</p><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Compensate speed differences between roll drive in the media-drawer and the X-transport drive. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Correct steering problems in the media feed. 
</p></li></ol><p class="- topic/p ">The performance of the buffer plate is monitored by two sensors (XMS_BUF_RIGHT_SE and XMS_BUF_LEFT_SE). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">These sensors register the position of the left and right side of the buffer plate. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">When the buffer plate moves inwards the value of the sensors increases and the roll drive will speed up to feed more media. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> If the buffer plate moves outwards the roll drive in the drawer will slow down to feed less media. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The values of these sensors are stored in the functional logging. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Distortion of the values indicate media issues before the X-transport drive (eg : Telescoping of media in the drawer). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Example: 
</p><fig id="GUID-79D5C9C8-257C-4326-B4BA-C00C9509227A" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-69A40699-0445-4C84-94A5-4D601E034F32-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-69A40699-0445-4C84-94A5-4D601E034F32-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">In the graph above an example is shown of the buffer plate logging. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The values of the sensors are plotted on the Y-axis (0-255). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The Blue line represent the left-sensor (or the left side of the media) and the Orange line represents the right-sensor (Right side of the media). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In the example above the Orange and Blue lines are moving parallel which indicates the media is pulled evenly from the drawer. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The absolute difference between the Orange and Blue lines can be corrected by 
<xref keyref="SDS15-6-018" class="- topic/xref " href="GUID-FCF3B250-0543-40FD-B0F2-511838FFF256.xml" format="dita" locktitle="yes" type="task"><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text 15-6-018 Check buffer plate [Special Tests]?>15-6-018 Check buffer plate [Special Tests]</xref>. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The values of the buffer plate sensors don’t have a direct relation with the visibility of the media step errors, but the performance of the buffer plate can point to a root cause of media step errors before the X-transport pinch. 
</p></section><section id="GUID-F58DD00A-D145-45EF-9FC4-5702E1AB1172" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Media step performance</title><p class="- topic/p ">The X-motion system of the media is handled by the media step control function. (see also : 
<xref keyref="15_FUNC_012" class="- topic/xref " href="GUID-B9BF590D-771F-4765-A31E-2131E70CDEB9.xml" format="dita" locktitle="yes" type="concept"><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text 15 The function of media step control?>15 The function of media step control</xref>). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This control function uses Automatic Advance Correction (AAC-markers) in combination with the M&amp;C-scanner to determine the position of the media on the platen. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Based on this information the needed media step correction is determined. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The AAC-markers (Normal or Enhanced) are located on the left and right side of the printed image (See example below). 
</p><fig id="GUID-B4D95D6B-659F-4242-8E83-B770B21DF14A" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-5FF03503-5C98-4F30-AE3E-90BDF091E7F6-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-5FF03503-5C98-4F30-AE3E-90BDF091E7F6-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The position of the markers in relation to the expected position is registered in the FLOG-data. 
</p><note id="GUID-C95E849D-E119-4214-B76E-A1488AC41B41" class="- topic/note "><p class="- topic/p ">Graphs created on these data are only showing the difference between the real position of these markers compared to the predicted position. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This means an user-defined deviation of the media-step like “Media step correction factor” will not be seen in these graphs. 
</p></note><p class="- topic/p ">Besides the media step errors the output of the media step controller is also registered. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The value of this output is an indication of the amount of correction which is needed to get the right media steps. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> A large value of this correction factor is an indication of a mismatch between the internal media calibration data and the real performance of the media on the platen. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">A large value doesn’t mean the media step errors will be seen on the printed image. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As mentioned it is only an indication of the performance of the media step function itself. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">If the media is calibrated correctly and the condition of the platen is not changed the output of the media step control function is just several µm to zero. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Example: 
</p><fig id="GUID-56BDEFC6-F31A-46F3-B98B-1029AE132D2B" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-0F00E48A-D450-4500-8EEB-11FF0BBAB99A-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-0F00E48A-D450-4500-8EEB-11FF0BBAB99A-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">In the graph above an example of the media step performance is shown of a 3 meter long print which is printed from the leading edge. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As the X-axis show the relative value compared to the leading edge, the most left value on the X-axis is in this case 0. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> In case the most left value isn’t 0 this means the print isn’t made directly from the leading edge, but made without cutting the last job. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">On the Y-axis the media step errors are shown in two colors (Blue and Orange) which are the left and right side of the printed image. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As can be seen the values on both sides initially starts at approx. +50 µm (Yellow zone). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As the error has a positive value the expected markers are further away than expected and might result in white lines. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> In case of a negative value dark lines might be excepted as the media steps will overlap. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">When the media step errors are within +/- 30 µm no deviations on the printed image are expected (green zone). 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> Media step errors between 30 and 100 µm might be visible (Yellow zone) depending of the used media. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Visibility of the media step errors on highly structured media as Canvas is less compared to smooth Self-Adhesive Media. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In case the errors are above 100 µm the media step errors will surely be seen (Red zone). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In the example above it can be seen the media step controller does not make any corrections until 50 cm after the leading edge. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">During this period the media is not covering all zones of the platen. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">After 50 cm the media step controller starts correcting the media step errors. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Within a few swaths the Orange and Blue lines are steered towards the green area. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In this case the media step controllers needs to correct every swath approx. 100 µm. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In this particular example the media is not calibrated well. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> This can be concluded from the fact media step errors are only visible in the first 50 cm after the leading edge when the media controller is not working yet. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> In case of a good calibration the media steps in the first 50 cm are predicted well and should already be within +/- 30 µm. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The second clue of a “bad” calibration is the fact the correction factor is above 100 µm. 
</p></section><section id="GUID-2B06DEFD-D8F9-4315-8619-DBCF86852811" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">PH performance</title><p class="- topic/p ">The quality of the printheads is monitored after every swath using the PAINt-algorithm (see also: 
<xref keyref="04-func-nozzle-failure" class="- topic/xref " href="GUID-B4CAA874-AEF6-4292-ACF9-46930A729737.xml" format="dita" locktitle="yes" type="concept"><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text xref?>04 The process of the Nozzle Failure detection, Nozzle Failure Compensation and PAINt</xref><xref keyref="04FUNC008" scope="local" format="dita" class="- topic/xref "><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text 04 The process of the Nozzle Failure detection, Nozzle Failure Compensation and PAINt?></xref>). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This algorithm can detect several causes of failing nozzles (eg. Air). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Based on these causes a nozzle can be classified as “Use”, ”Avoid” or “Don’t use”. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">When a nozzle is classified as “Don’t use” it will not be used during the rest of the print. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This means this nozzle needs to be compensated by NFC. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Nozzles which are classified as “Avoid” aren’t used unless there are no other options left. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Besides this dynamic behavior of NFC the amount of marked nozzles during the “Nozzle optimalisation” procedure also contribute to the final result of the print quality. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Of course there is a relationship between the amount of failing nozzles and the final print quality. However this is not a strict relationship. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> For example: 
</p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> A failing black nozzle might be compensated by another black nozzle in the next swath or even by CMY nozzles. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">A failing nozzle in yellow is less visible in print quality comparing to a black failure. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Multiple failing nozzles next to each other are harder to compensate compared to the same amount of separated nozzles. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Not all nozzles might be needed in the next swath 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Multi pass print modes are more likely to compensate failing nozzles. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">.... 
</p></li></ul><p class="- topic/p ">Given these dependencies there cannot be given a hard number of failing nozzles which will result in print quality issues. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">No printhead may be replaced solitary based on printhead performance graphs.</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b "> These graphs are only to be used as support for an already suspected quality issue.</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">There are two different graphs which represent the printhead performance (Printhead score and nozzle performance). 
</p><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Printhead score:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The performance of the printheads is measured on an arbitrary scale from 0 to 10, where 10 is the best performance and 0 the worst performance. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This score can be used to get an overall impression of the performance of the printheads (In case further details are required the “Nozzle performance” can be used). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As already mentioned the resulting print quality depends of many factors so this score cannot be used as an absolute criteria for a good or bad printhead. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Of course a lower score has more likelihood to result in low print quality. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In case a customer is not complaining about a specific color there is no reason the replace a printhead with a lower score. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This graph should be used to find specific events which might resulted in low print quality. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Example: 
</p><fig id="GUID-44C74804-FC2E-43E0-9C1A-6D1D79270FAE" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-B57D5BFD-0A33-4BD2-A4C7-DAC09D945D29-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-B57D5BFD-0A33-4BD2-A4C7-DAC09D945D29-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The graph above shows the printhead score of every printhead over a specific timeframe. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Every printhead has its own colored line. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In the example above an event happened in June 2022 on Y8 (light yellow line) and another event in October 2022 in K4 (black line). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Both events caused the printhead score to drop permanently for both printheads (Deeper analyses shows that in this case a major media crash caused a loose nozzleplate). 
</p><note id="GUID-26D6DCAA-E776-4AE6-8029-4AD35B1C97F3" class="- topic/note "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Important Note regarding White:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">When not refreshed UVgel ink can dry out at the nozzles. This is mainly observed in the white-printhead of the CMxx-series. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This happens when a customer is printing CMYK instead of CMYK-W. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As a result of the dryed out nozzles the printhead score of the White-printhead will drastically drop. (see screenshot below). 
</p><fig id="GUID-9975E981-B987-4C77-A03E-960E18D7D1BD" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-75A8BB90-08BB-431D-AB73-6861B6A130C7-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-75A8BB90-08BB-431D-AB73-6861B6A130C7-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p "> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">However the CMxx is capable of detecting this issue and will recover the white-printhead before the next CYMKW-print. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This will result in a unstable score. However during printing everything will be according to expectations 
</p></note><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Nozzle performance:</b> This complex graph shows the performance of each nozzle of every printhead after every swath during a print. This graph can be used to determine the rootcause in case of a low printhead score . 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The nozzle performance is a 2D representation of the nozzle performance after every swath during a print. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">On the vertical-axis the SwathID is shown. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The first swath of a print has SwathID 0 and the last swithID is depended of the length of print. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This can vary between 10 to thousands. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">On the horizontal axis every nozzleID is shown. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The first nozzle of the 1st printhead has NozzleID 1 and is shown on the left side of the graph. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">A printhead in the Colorado platform has 2 array’s which numbering continues. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This means in case an array has 256 nozzles the 1st nozzle of the second array has nozzleID 257. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Every printhead has a unique color and is represented in that way in the background. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In case a nozzle is deviating during a print this deviation is plotted as a different color. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Every type of deviation has an unique color. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">For example: Air at the nozzle (AN) has a blue color as and electrical Open Circuit (OC) has a Yellow color. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In the graph below an example of the nozzle performance graph is shown. 
</p><fig id="GUID-AD15FF44-B3B4-4838-8619-6EF7F210C966" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-CBAA5BFC-C930-4195-878B-F4EFBB6D89FF-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-CBAA5BFC-C930-4195-878B-F4EFBB6D89FF-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">As can be seen one nozzle in the Cyan printhead (C2) is failing on classification DNJN between swathID 200 and 300. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As the nozzleID is 382 this means it is the 1st nozzle of the second array of C2. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> In Y8 a nozzle is permanently classified as DNJN. 
</p><note id="GUID-165F48A9-3A1B-4B36-A432-C6F253350AD8" class="- topic/note "><p class="- topic/p ">As mentioned this graph should only be used for pattern recognition to find root causes of failures. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The absolute amount of failing nozzles and the classifications should not be used as criteria to replace a printhead. 
</p></note><p class="- topic/p ">Besides this 2D representation there is also a graph showing the absolute position of the failing nozzles during a specified swath. 
</p><fig id="GUID-929E117A-F963-4B30-95DE-F7D02F56F8EC" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-E07906B2-2D0C-46DF-9830-C36A7548ADA3-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-E07906B2-2D0C-46DF-9830-C36A7548ADA3-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The example above shows 4 printheads from the C1630. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">As can be seen 1 printhead consists of 2 MEMS-chips which have 2 arrays. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In this example there is a cluster of Open Circuits (OC) in the Magenta printhead. 
</p></section><section id="GUID-13BF8AA0-5C7F-4F81-940D-B2D8ED5ABFD1" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">ECID information</title><p class="- topic/p ">Every print job which is send to the Colorado printer has unique properties. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The most important properties have been summarized in the ECID information. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This information contains 5 tables. 
</p><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">General information:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This part shows the unique properties of the print like timestamp and ECID. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Media information: 
</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">All information regarding the selected media is shown in this table. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">However there can be a difference between the selected media and the media on the platen. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The engine cannot detect the real media on the platen. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The only information stored is the media which has been selected by the customer in the RIP. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Profile settings: 
</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Properties set in the RIP-profile are shown in this table. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Job settings:</b> 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The settings of the job like requested print quality and output settings are shown in this table. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Job Content 
</b>: 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Detailed information regarding the content of the job are shown in this table. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The exact content of an image is NOT stored or logged. 
</p></li></ol><p class="- topic/p ">Example: 
</p><fig id="GUID-0F1B9DB6-FD67-400B-80C5-292B0A274E9A" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-F2F576E0-CC7C-4008-A721-2B3B77BFDE9F-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-F2F576E0-CC7C-4008-A721-2B3B77BFDE9F-low.png"/></fig></section><section id="GUID-86D2D265-D0BB-4867-9077-7104A6A40D4E" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Ink Expiry date</title><p class="- topic/p ">The UVgel ink has an expiry date like all other UV inks. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The ink will slowly change its properties when aging. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Light and heat will increase the aging effect. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Under normal transport and storage conditions the ink is good to use for one year after production (see also 
<xref keyref="02FUNC010" class="- topic/xref " href="GUID-25E92BBA-A9A6-4169-B0A1-3A043E52BF09.xml" format="dita" locktitle="yes" type="concept"><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text 02 The function of the Ink Supply PBA (02PBA01)?>02 Ink expiration</xref>). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">After that time, the ink properties might have changed so that print quality cannot be guaranteed anymore. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The expiry date of the ink bottle is programmed into the RFID chip of the bottle. 
</p><p class="- topic/p "> For the ink inside the printer, an expiry date is calculated and shown on the operator panel. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">There is one expiry date for each color. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The expiry date of the ink inside the printer is a weighted average of the current ink in the jar + the newly added bottle. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Every 45 second the expiry date of the ink inside the ink tank is calculated. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Example: 
</p><fig id="GUID-5C605D4B-486A-42D8-9AC8-9A143108C565" class="- topic/fig "><image href="GUID-E5C1FA15-5F05-45B0-B621-90AED92F7FF7-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-E5C1FA15-5F05-45B0-B621-90AED92F7FF7-low.png"/></fig><p class="- topic/p ">The graph shows 4 different lines which represent the remaining expiry date in days(1 for each color). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">If ink is expired the value of the remaining expiry date will be below zero. (Red area in the graph). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The slope of these lines is equal to -1. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This means every day the remaining expiry date will decrease by 1 day. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">When the ink tank is refilled by a new ink bottle the line will make a steep step upwards. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The size of this step is depended of the amount of ink before refilling and the remaining shelf life of the ink bottle. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">A small step means the remaining expiry date of the new ink bottle is almost the same as the remaining expiry date in the ink tank. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">If the remaining expiry date is below 0 warning 290020 will be given and a message on the UI will be presented. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">When the ink has been refilled using a new ink bottle the remaining expiry date will be above 0 again, but this event is not logged in the engine. 
</p></section></taskbody><related-links class="- topic/related-links "><linkpool class="- topic/linkpool " mapkeyref="GUID-8A41CFEA-5928-4042-A2CB-507A5D034160"><link class="- topic/link " mapclass="- map/topicref " format="dita" type="concept" href="generated-topic-GUID-5C744D2A-FEF2-4862-8FE5-FD7BF98BAD6C.xml" role="parent"><?ditaot usertext?><linktext class="- topic/linktext "><?ditaot usertext?>FLOG-data</linktext></link></linkpool></related-links>
</task>