<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?ish ishref="GUID-63532B05-B9C7-42D0-A78B-C255C34E34B0" version="2" lang="en-US"?><concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="GUID-63532B05-B9C7-42D0-A78B-C255C34E34B0" xml:lang="en-US" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic concept)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            a(base ishcondition)                            a(base varid)                            a(base varref)                            a(base cid)                            a(base partslist)                            (topic oce-d)                            (topic sdlVariables-c)                            (topic oceCommonElements-c)                            (topic oceMetaDecl-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c concept oceConcept-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c hi-d oceHighlight-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c ui-d oceUi-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c sw-d oceSoftware-c)   " class="- topic/topic concept/concept "><title class="- topic/title ">Safety and Environmental Related Incidents</title><abstract class="- topic/abstract " id="GUID-3DFBAFD2-FF3E-4DCB-BE62-B63E71637782"><p class="- topic/p ">To assure that Root Cause Analysis of Safety and Environmental related Field Issues can be executed accurately by Canon Production Printing it is expected that actions shall be taken by Canon NSO, Canon RSHQ and/or dealer. Safety and Environmental related Field Issues are occurrences with Canon Production Printing products, materials and/or its packaging that are put on the market which threaten the safety, environment and/or health of bystander(s), service technician(s), customer(s), users and operators . This (can) result in human injury and/or material damage. Relevant occurrences include findings that indicate a potential non-conformity with safety or environmental regulations. Always report Safety and Environmental related Field Issues via a Trust call. Trust is an application that supports the solution finding process within Canon Production Printing on issues that occur at customer locations. The Canon Production Printing policy is that the Field Issues shall be handled by all related stakeholders with highest priority and urgency. This applies to the activities in relation to Field Issues and where immediate action of the Canon Production Printing organization is essential regarding: 
</p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> minimizing the (potential) impact on customers, Canon Production Printing and Canon Inc; 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> limiting the risk of product liability; 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> obtaining all relevant information to find the cause and prevent repetition; 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> maintaining the customer's confidence in Canon Production Printing and Canon INC. 
</p></li></ul></abstract><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><metadata class="- topic/metadata "><category class="- topic/category ">Functional description</category></metadata></prolog><conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody "><section id="GUID-57EC32A9-4F89-4CE5-8D99-D529834493C0" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Field Safety Issue (FSI)</title><p class="- topic/p ">A FSI is an undesirable or unfortunate event that occurs unforeseen, unplanned unintentionally or unexpectedly, without a deliberate plan or cause and usually results in harm, injury, damage, or loss; casualty and in an increase in liabilities. Non-conformity (non-compliance) with any condition of approval, license condition, safety regulation or any other statutory approval or requirement relevant to the activity and/or area where the activity occurs. Important trigger FSI keywords are bleed, burn, cut, fire, flame, hazard, leak, melt, noise, odor, emission, chemical, damage, sharp, shock, smell, smoke, snag, spark, food safety, food non-compliance, food packaging, and stumble or any form (e.g. -ed, -ing, -s) of these words. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Important note: Also a “near miss” with safety implications should be reported as a Field Issue; unplanned or potential events that did not result in an FI, but had the potential to do so. 
</p></section><section id="GUID-3DD38D1B-47CF-4B51-92C5-C4AF2C82EDB3" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">What is a Field Environmental Issue (FEI) </title><p class="- topic/p ">A FEI is an undesirable or unfortunate event that occurs unforeseen, unplanned unintentionally or unexpectedly, without a deliberate plan or cause and usually results as a consequence of which pollution (air, water, noise, or land) or an adverse environmental impact has occurred, is occurring, or is likely to occur. Adverse environmental impact includes contamination, harm to flora and fauna (either individual species or communities), damage to heritage items and adverse community impacts. A non-conformity (non-compliance) has any condition of approval, license condition, environmental regulation or any other statutory approval or requirement relevant to the activity and/or area where the activity occurs. Important trigger FEIs keywords are disposal, leak, melt, odor, emission, chemical, pollution or any form (e.g. -ed, -ing, -s) of these words. 
</p></section><section id="GUID-57F9B29C-2077-4B47-9A87-195E96990537" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">How to handle</title><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Service RSHQ/NSO/dealer will notify Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing as soon as possible on occurrence of the incident. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Service RSHQ/NSO/dealer will advise the customer to not use the printer, switch the printer off and disconnect the mains plug. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Service RSHQ/NSO/dealer will not start repairs before having agreement with Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing . 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing will notify acceptance to Service NSO/Region within 1 working day of initial notification. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Service RSHQ/NSO/dealer will supply details on the field issue ultimately within 5 calendar days: 
</p><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Write a Trust report: 
</p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Issue type: Field issue 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Problem class: Safety/Environmental. 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Fill out the part “Field Safety Incidents” of the Trust report (see Information Bulletin 0000 that gives a detailed list off the required info). 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Collect AllTraceData (log files) and attached the files to the Trust report. 
</p></li></ul></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Send affected parts to Service Canon Production Printing for investigation.<sup class="+ topic/ph hi-d/sup ">*1</sup> 
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> If the affected system is beyond repair, it needs to be held available for Canon Production Printing inspection. 
</p></li></ol></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing will track/trace/communicate proceedings via a Priority 1 Problem Report. 
</p></li></ol><p class="- topic/p "><sup class="+ topic/ph hi-d/sup ">*1</sup> Parts need to be sent to the Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing contact via courier with shortest possible lead time (within 5 days delivery to Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing desk). Service &amp; Support Canon Production Printing will supply the technician on-site with a retour label for dropping off/sending the part(s) to a designated Canon Production Printing address.
</p></section></conbody></concept>