<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?ish ishref="GUID-31F1F21C-6ECA-4297-8787-5C0C82B13981" version="10" lang="en-US"?><concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="GUID-31F1F21C-6ECA-4297-8787-5C0C82B13981" xml:lang="en-US" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic concept)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            a(base ishcondition)                            a(base varid)                            a(base varref)                            a(base cid)                            a(base partslist)                            (topic oce-d)                            (topic sdlVariables-c)                            (topic oceCommonElements-c)                            (topic oceMetaDecl-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c concept oceConcept-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c hi-d oceHighlight-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c ui-d oceUi-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c sw-d oceSoftware-c)   " class="- topic/topic concept/concept "><title class="- topic/title ">What is <ph translate="no" class="- topic/ph ">On Remote Service</ph> (ORS) ?</title><abstract class="- topic/abstract " id="M148684-B19"><p class="- topic/p "><ph class="- topic/ph " translate="no">On Remote Service</ph> is a comprehensive offering of partially automated services that provides :
</p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Higher uptime, smoother operation
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">Real-time troubleshooting
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p ">100 % secure and under your control
</p></li></ul><fig class="- topic/fig " id="GUID-F290D4DF-2A8B-4BC5-B785-6603461ED96D"><title class="- topic/title "/><image class="- topic/image " href="GUID-3B7EE889-36AD-45C9-9B7C-BEB1F2F2A962-low.png" placement="inline" otherprops="GUID-3B7EE889-36AD-45C9-9B7C-BEB1F2F2A962-low.png"/></fig></abstract><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><metadata class="- topic/metadata "><category class="- topic/category ">Functional description</category></metadata></prolog><conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody "><section id="M148684-B20" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Reliability and flexibility are key</title><p class="- topic/p ">With print production windows narrower than ever, and with high workloads per engine, today’s print professionals are looking for nothing less than totally reliable
</p><p class="- topic/p ">print operation, delivered by printers that offer maximum uptime. These are demands that Canon understands: our printing systems are built around proven technology and robust design, guaranteeing dependable operation.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Alongside the product itself, service is also a vital part of reliability. Here too, Canon stands out. Our Canon Service Organizations have a deserved record of excellence, and use state-of-the-art tools and remote capabilities to make our systems even more reliable. Canon’s ongoing commitment to innovation embraces the development of advanced service concepts and solutions, as well as quality products.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">ORS – On Remote Service – a productivity-focused toolset – can increase uptime and offers preventive capabilities.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Within ongoing projects for our latest family of printers, it even opens predictive capabilities, taking uptime to new levels.
</p></section><section id="GUID-BF760B0A-98B2-42AB-A4A2-EA41BE7E6DC5" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">State-of-the-art support</title><p class="- topic/p ">Working through secure connections between Canon printing systems and the Data Center, ORS is a comprehensive offering of partly-automated services that maximize uptime and minimize administrative effort. A higher level of service support can be delivered to systems remotely: engineers can carry out problem analysis, recovery or workarounds without having to be on site at the printing system’s location.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The result: maximum productivity through increased uptime, and the possibility to troubleshoot in real time.
</p></section><section id="GUID-C6F307C9-C979-49C2-9DCB-E2861C722C84" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">The benefits</title><p class="- topic/p ">The main benefit of ORS is that it can give you higher uptime and greater availability. Analysis of the printing system can be started much earlier. Before making an on-site service visit, the service technician has all the required information on hand in advance for better preparation. This makes the troubleshooting process faster, thereby resulting in less downtime.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Monitoring capabilities are also available, which offers even greater efficiency benefits. And if operators need assistance, for example with settings for print jobs that are run only infrequently, they can call a Canon Service representative, who will give support remotely.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">ORS is designed for ease of use and smooth operation: meter readings and diagnostics data can be communicated automatically, saving time and reducing administrative effort. Using ORS will also unlock further benefit downstream: automated capture of knowledge and experience helps us to improve our printing systems and design them even more closely around the needs of our customers.
</p></section><section id="GUID-F6A4C16B-4E64-4F4A-BF77-9253E5215CFE" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Secure and under your control</title><p class="- topic/p "> Security of operation is paramount in any business operation.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">That’s why Canon’s policy is simple – you always stay in full control with respect to ORS:
</p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> ORS functionality is activated only when you are clear on what it entails, and have given your agreement.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> You are consulted on all the settings that are needed to establish the remote connection.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> Remote Assistance sessions are never started without your express permission – e.g. confirmation via on-screen button.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> No data is retrieved from the print engine other than meter readings, diagnostic information and remote channel status details. No customer data or print job data is retrieved.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> All connections are secure, and all the data communicated is encrypted to HTTPS industry standard or sent via a secure, dedicated VPN tunnel, the global standard for confidential transactions in corporate information systems.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Canon can provide you with its security white paper on request.
</p></li></ul></section><section id="GUID-9767FDC0-7B66-420B-B999-5A5A7C20F328" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">ORS consists of five interrelated components</title><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">ORS Remote Diagnostics</b>: 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This service receives automated eventbased service data from the engine.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The Service team uses this data to identify and analyze device status and determine appropriate action in the event any issue is pending. If a service intervention is needed, it can be prepared optimally using this data, thereby minimizing or even preventing downtime. Through Event Forwarding, the printing system can even be programmed to alert Canon upon defined events.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">ORS Remote Assistance</b>: 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Should questions related to configuration or settings arise, On Remote Assistance enables an Canon representative, with your consent, to connect remotely to your system. Only machine data is transferred; your print job data remains completely untouched. The Canon representative can observe the current status of the system and make adjustments if needed.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">ORS Content Service</b>:
</p><p class="- topic/p "> Functional Logging enables Canon to conduct performance analysis and monitor in real time. The logged information consists of sensor and timing data.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">No print job data is touched. Service such as Performance Dashboards and Mobile Alerting are stepping stones for innovative services to come.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">ORS Remote Meter Reads</b>:
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This function remotely requests device counter information on a periodic basis, eliminating the need for you to read the data manually and communicate it to Canon.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">ORS Remote Software-Distribution</b>:
</p><p class="- topic/p ">On Remote Software-Distribution lets you update the printer device with the latest printer software. This is entirely under your control, since the software is only downloaded to the device on your specific request.
</p></li></ol></section><section id="GUID-4F067429-0548-4BF0-9913-670E06FF3012" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title "/><fig id="GUID-EE4DA7A9-AF2A-4324-B101-54FFFCE8A9D0" class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title "/><image href="GUID-14861BFD-E163-4ACB-8032-0AAE831CD811-low.png" placement="inline" class="- topic/image " otherprops="GUID-14861BFD-E163-4ACB-8032-0AAE831CD811-low.png"/></fig></section></conbody><related-links class="- topic/related-links "><linkpool class="- topic/linkpool " mapkeyref="GUID-8A41CFEA-5928-4042-A2CB-507A5D034160"><link class="- topic/link " mapclass="- map/topicref " format="dita" type="concept" href="generated-topic-GUID-DFD95E44-6FE2-4690-855D-446A64ABF90C.xml" role="parent"><?ditaot usertext?><linktext class="- topic/linktext "><?ditaot usertext?>ORS: On Remote Service</linktext></link></linkpool></related-links>
</concept>