<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?ish ishref="GUID-199ACF8A-08D6-40B5-ABE6-FDD389DF3CAD" version="1" lang="en-US"?><task xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="GUID-199ACF8A-08D6-40B5-ABE6-FDD389DF3CAD" xml:lang="en-US" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic task)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            a(base ishcondition)                            a(base varid)                            a(base varref)                            a(base cid)                            a(base partslist)                            (topic oce-d)                            (topic sdlVariables-c)                            (topic oceCommonElements-c)                            (topic oceMetaDecl-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c task oceTask-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c hi-d oceHighlight-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c ui-d oceUi-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c sw-d oceSoftware-c)   " class="- topic/topic task/task "><title class="- topic/title ">How to use the print quality section of the TSM</title><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><metadata class="- topic/metadata "><category class="- topic/category ">Diagnostics</category></metadata></prolog><taskbody class="- topic/body task/taskbody "><section id="GUID-07E4226A-4024-411D-84BE-014C55029E8C" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Disclaimer:</title><p class="- topic/p ">This part of the TSM is written based on shared knowledge regarding the diagnostics of print quality issues. We tried to be as complete as possible, but of course, new defects/artifacts may arise. In those cases use the annotation process to request new diagnostics.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The documents are written from the point of view the customer is unable to use or sell the affected print. This means the print quality is assumed to be outside the specifications of the engine and/or application. See “<xref keyref="Workflow_troubleshoot_PQ" class="- topic/xref " href="GUID-11C3F6FD-8128-4D1C-910D-2BB3D7D8A019.xml" format="dita" locktitle="yes" type="tsTroubleshooting"><?ditaot usertext?><?xm-replace_text How to distinguish between technical or application related PQ-issues?>How to distinguish between technical or application related PQ-issues</xref>” on how to check if the engine is within specification. 
</p></section><section id="GUID-C9E39E2C-6841-4EEC-8AED-CA9CC071B25A" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Process flow:</title><p class="- topic/p ">The usage of this section of the TSM starts from the moment the customer calls the helpdesk/support team about print quality issues. This means the helpdesk/support team can use this section of the TSM to prevent unnecessary service visits or application support by asking for additional information/analyses from the customer.
</p><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> The first step is to determine the issue the customer is referring to. This can be a complex process as in some cases the information can only be gathered by asking questions to the customer instead of a visual reference to the affected print.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Another approach to finding the right issue is to visually compare the affected print with the examples given in the overview. This overview is split into different chapters which are grouped by the orientation or appearance of artifacts.
</p></li><li class="- topic/li "><p class="- topic/p "> After finding the correct page the process flow mentioned in the issue page can be used to perform a structured analysis and minimizes the time of diagnostics/repair.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">An important aspect of the process flow in the issue pages is the responsibility of the different roles. The first step is always a remote analysis by the helpdesk. Depending on these analyses an engineer or application specialist can be sent to the customer to solve the issue. 
</p></li></ol></section><section id="GUID-10FA026F-AD7A-4251-8F73-520072A107B1" class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">The layout of the documents:</title><p class="- topic/p ">The issue pages contain 4 chapters: Collect/ Analyze/ Repair and Evaluate. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In the first chapter, information is given about the properties of the mentioned issue. This information can be used to verify if the correct page is being viewed. A part of this chapter is ADAM triggers. In some cases, information available in the back-office is already pinpointing a specific defect or helps to diagnose a problem. In those cases, a trigger is present in ADAM (eg : 04-T-001 : Loose nozzleplate detected). 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">The main chapter of the issue page is the Analyze/Repair. This chapter describes a structured way of working to solve the issue using a flowchart. The flowchart starts at icon number 1 and based on the answers/results of it continues downwards. If the issue is solved halfway through the flowchart there is no need to continue the flowchart. A detailed description of each icon can be found in the table below the flowchart (Step explanation).
</p><p class="- topic/p ">After resolving the issue the last chapter can be used to inform the customer on how to prevent this issue from happing again. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">In case the reader of the document wants to learn more about the issue the chapter “Background info” can be read. This chapter describes more insides of the issue but is not necessary to solve the issue. 
</p></section></taskbody><related-links class="- topic/related-links "><linkpool class="- topic/linkpool " mapkeyref="GUID-8A41CFEA-5928-4042-A2CB-507A5D034160"><link class="- topic/link " mapclass="- map/topicref " format="dita" type="concept" href="generated-topic-GUID-EF42FFF3-C6AF-4939-AE5C-9EB2061E0E1B.xml" role="parent"><?ditaot usertext?><linktext class="- topic/linktext "><?ditaot usertext?>Image Quality</linktext></link></linkpool></related-links>
</task>