<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?ish ishref="GUID-0CB9FECA-B8CA-48FE-A1CE-BCD5B4AE9A75" version="1" lang="en-US"?><tsTroubleshooting xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="GUID-0CB9FECA-B8CA-48FE-A1CE-BCD5B4AE9A75" xml:lang="en-US" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2" domains="(topic tsTroubleshooting)                            (topic hi-d)    (topic sdlVariables-c)                             (topic ut-d)                             (topic indexing-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic oce-d)                            (topic oceCommonElements-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c hi-d oceHighlight-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c ui-d oceUi-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c sw-d oceSoftware-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c task oceTask-c)                            (topic oceTopic-c tsTroubleshooting oceTroubleshooting-c)   " class="- topic/topic tsTroubleshooting/tsTroubleshooting "><title translate="no" class="- topic/title "> Media position not stable in Y-direction on the platen (Jumbo Roll Interface)</title><abstract class="- topic/abstract " id="GUID-B87BF88B-91B2-4C27-A55C-91B9B6986C8A"><p class="- topic/p ">When using the Jumbo roll interface the media position is not stable in Y-direction on platen.
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Possible solution:
</p><p class="- topic/p ">Check first if the media from media roll 1 or 2 is functioning correctly. This must be correct.
</p><p class="- topic/p "> Stabilize the paper feed in Y (cross) direction:
</p><p class="- topic/p "> When loading the Jumbo roll the chance of misalignment of the media towards the printer is bigger then when media is loaded in the media drawer. As a consequence the media tends to move in cross-direction over the platen (print surface) during the first 1-2 meters. For calibration and printing it is important to stabilize this cross direction movement first. 
</p><p class="- topic/p ">This can be done by feeding the media via forward transport on the operator panel of the system. When judging the cross direction movement the position of the media edge in relation to the X-tran rollers at the media entrance side of the print surface is a good reference point. Once this edge is stabilized, it is possible to do the calibration or in case that has already been performed earlier, to start printing. Typically a length of 1 m is needed to stabilize the media movement.
</p></abstract><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><metadata class="- topic/metadata "><category class="- topic/category ">Diagnostics</category></metadata></prolog><related-links class="- topic/related-links "><linkpool class="- topic/linkpool " mapkeyref="GUID-8A41CFEA-5928-4042-A2CB-507A5D034160"><link class="- topic/link " mapclass="- map/topicref " format="dita" type="concept" href="generated-topic-GUID-5090EA3B-AAF0-41F4-8B92-98B5E855EB33.xml" role="parent"><?ditaot usertext?><linktext class="- topic/linktext "><?ditaot usertext?>Diagnostics</linktext></link></linkpool></related-links>
</tsTroubleshooting>